# **Dzvinka Mytsyk**

Email: <u>dzvinka.mytsyk@gmail.com</u>

Skype: dzvenyslava.mytsyk Residence: Berlin, Germany

LinkedIn: <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/dzvinkamytsyk">http://www.linkedin.com/in/dzvinkamytsyk</a>

Mobile: +49 157 386 46 321

Nationality: Ukrainian



# Senior Business Analyst, Product Owner

I am highly professional IT business analyst with experience across different domains. I have successful experience in Product Management, Product Ownership and in leading a software development team as Scrum Master and Project Manager. I am very passionate about agile methodologies, software development practices and paradigms.

# **PROVEN SKILLS**

Lean, Scrum and Agile Software life cycle management

Software requirements management Change management

Strong analytical skills Quick learner (new domains)

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

#### Ringier AG — Berlin, Germany

**April 2014 - June 2014** 

## Freelance Project Manager - EMS migration project

Customer: Internal Ringier project

Project: migrating Ringier websites from existing legacy EMS systems to SailThru EMS

Role: coordinate multi-functional teams from 7 countries in Asia and Africa: marketing, creative and IT.

# Key results:

- Marketing specification for 10+ websites prepared
- IT scope defined and WBS prepared
- Creative scope defined and delivered

# <u>Epam Systems</u> (NYSE: EPAM) — Budapest, Hungary & Kyiv, Ukraine

One of the biggest outsourcing software services and solutions providers from Central and Eastern Europe. EPAM provides expert consulting, development, testing, support and infrastructure services to many of the world's leading organizations like Barclays Capital, UBS, Boeing, etc. Distributed delivery model includes mix of Onshore/NearShore and Offshore approaches.

## <u>Search Engine Analyst, Scrum Mater – WK project</u>

Customer: Wolters Kluwer

Project: multinational document search platform (based on Microsoft Fast search engine).

Role: search engine configuration, optimization and trouble shooting; new search requirements implementation

and new platform releases roll-outs; Agile process coordination.

#### Key results:

- Several successful releases of search engine for multi-lingual international deployments
- Innovative ideas accepted by customers: UI redesign, documentation process improvement, etc.

#### Senior Business Analyst, deputy Product Owner - FuSA project

Customer: UBS AG

Project: Bank's internal software for settlements and confirmations processing

*Role*: requirements clarification and documentation, deputy Product Owner on several sub-projects, Scrum Master on several iterations, xsd and xslt development, sql scripting, test cases and test scenarios creation, taking part in QA process.

#### Key results:

- · Successful implementation and deployment of commodities derivatives trades processing
- Successful CDS trade processing re-engineering and support

#### Project Manager, Business Analyst - CMP project

Customer: Clarabridge

Project: Text mining engine and natural language processing

*Role*: distributed team management, QA management, negotiations with customers, product strategy development and execution control; business processes analysis; software requirements writing.

# Key results:

- Multiple successful releases of natural language processing module
- · Implementation and deployment of QA on-line monitoring system

# <u>Project Manager / Business Analyst — Cactus System</u>

Customer: EPAM Systems

Project: Internal tool for contractor employees accounting process

*Role*: distributed team management (4 offices, up to 30 team members); project planning, progress monitoring and control; entire project's documentation review; negotiations with customers and business processes analysis; software requirements writing; communication with development and testing teams.

#### Key results:

- Managing project from the start, creating a team, implementing Scrum processes
- Successful releases and deployment of several versions of the system for EPAM's internal accounting department

# **Business Analyst — Phoenix System re-engineering**

Project: re-engineering of existing system for health insurance company in USA

*Role*: negotiations with customers and business processes analysis; software requirements writing; communication with development and testing teams.

#### Key results:

· Creating comprehensive requirements set (including wire-frames) for the first phase of re-engineering

# Ukrainian Mobile Communications — Kyiv, Ukraine (now MTS Ukraine)

November 2005 - June 2006

One of the largest mobile operator in Ukraine. In 1993, it was the first company to introduce mobile (cellular) services in Ukraine. As of today, Ukrainian MTS network support various value-added services based on GPRS / EGPRS / EDGE and SMS / WAP / MMS / USSD. MTS is the only BlackBerry service provider in Ukraine and is also a service provider of WiFi hotspots, mainly in large cities and airports.

#### Project Coordinator - "Coverage complaints processing database"

Role: project planning; software requirements analysis; execution, monitoring and control; negotiation with stakeholders.

#### Key results:

- Created a full process description of mobile coverage complaints processing.
- Successful release, deployment and maintenance of the overage complaints DB.

## Mirasoft-Group Corp — Kyiv, Ukraine

June 2004 - October 2005

Mirasoft is a Ukrainian provider of software outsourcing services. Mirasoft specializes in the development of business administration tools, document management and work-flow solutions and electronic medical systems has industry-specific expertise in several business sectors, including financial, technology, telecom and health-care.

# <u>Project Manager – IPLocks Automated Test System Development</u>

Project: Creating new QA-automation software solution

Role: project planning; execution, monitoring and control; risk management; communication with customer and internal communication; reporting; quality planning, assurance and control; human resource management, team

development, coaching & trainings & hiring, project processes development and deployment.

#### Key results:

- Successful prototype creation which retained a new customer
- Released several versions of QA-automation software
- Increased the team from initial 2 people to 10-15 (in different phases)

## **Business processes Analyst - CMMI Deployment**

*Project*: CMMI processes deployment throughout the company, CMMI level 3 certification *Role*: CMMI training participation, organizational and project processes development and deployment, internal processes trainings creation and presentation.

# Key results:

- 3 CMMI processes trainings prepared and delivered
- 3 CMMI processes tailored and deployed into projects life-cycle

## **Business Analyst — Top Dog**

*Project*: travel web-service application development – hotel booking, planes tickets, car rental *Role*: software requirements specification analysis, design documents creation, technical specification preparation, QA, project processes development and deployment.

# Key results:

• Successful integration of 5 service providers into the system (specification, QA coordination, acceptance)

# ICC Company - Kyiv, Ukraine

October 2003 - May 2004

ICC – web-development company, part of large Ukrainian publishing house "SoftPress". Main purpose – create and support web-sites of published magazines.

# <u>Software Developer - multiple web-projects</u>

Project: create and support web-sites of published magazines

Role: database structure development, design development, php code, sql scripts.

EDUCATION	
National University of "Kyiv-Mohyla Academy" — Kyiv, Ukraine	
Bachelor's degree in Computer Science	1999 - 2003
Secondary School #47 - Lviv, Ukraine	
Secondary education completed with the Gold Medal for High Honors	1988 - 1999

TECHNICAL QUALIFICATIONS		
BA skills	Requirements documentation and management, requirements elicitation techniques	
Domain experience	Investment banking; Search optimization; Natural Language Processing; Travel; Email marketing;	
Product Management	Product backlog management, Product Vision, Product Roadmap, A/B testing, MVP and MMP, MVP metrics	
UX and UI	Balsamiq, Visio, Gluffy, UX principles, Lean UX, Usability testing	
Programming Languages	SQL, HTML, XML, XSLT, JSON, Java basic skills	
Methodologies and programmi paradigms	ing Agile, Lean, XP, Scrum, Kanban, RUP, OOP, TDD, OKR	
Project Management Tools	Trello, JIRA, Confluence, MS Project	
Databases	PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle - understanding and ability to create complex DB schemas , hands on as user	
Enterprise frameworks	Understanding of J2EE technologies	
Version & revision control	Git, Subversion, CVS	
Operation systems	Microsoft Windows, GNU/Linux	
Spoken languages	English – fluent, Ukrainian – native, Russian – bilingual,	

Polish - intermediate, French - intermediate, German - novice